Hey again. In this second video, I will talk about how I used AI
to build this. So, first of all,
it all starts with this repository I have that's called Muthur, from the
Alien spaceship, which I use for all of my repositories,
and which contains the execution loop and the skills,
the rule sets, everything that you need to build with agents,
everything that I need to build with agents,
regardless of the stack that you use.
Initially, I used it to make a clone, or a so-called spin-off,
of my own professional website.
And when I say spin-off, it means that it copied not just its design
system but, more importantly, its coding discipline,
which means the very strict linter rules,
the Feature-Sliced Design approach, and a lot of additional checks
that I added along the way as I was developing my website, and that
I also use in other apps of mine.
Then I used the brief that I had for the assessment to come
up with a plan, which is pretty high level,
and from there I went to implementing it with Claude
Code. Usually, I would go about it in a way where I would split
it into a lot of pieces and then implement them one by one,
each via its own pull request. But here I went in a different direction.
I made it all on one feature branch and
one pull request, because of the time constraints
and the nature of the task. What's important is that, despite this,
it was never overflowing the context of the LLM,
because I have this approach, from the skills that I use from this Muthur
repo, which is to have a plan inside
the repo. And whenever one agent finishes its small piece of work, which is
within, let's say, 200,000 tokens,
it will pause the plan. Here's what it actually looks like.
So it puts the plan on pause, and then I can start a new
session with this plan,
just saying "go", and it will go do the next chunk, and so on
and so on. And so from there, in about a hundred commits with
two hundred and fifty files, we got to a stage where we had an app
that was actually working. And it was pretty well structured
from the get-go. First of all, because we had these forks during which I
checked that it looked as I wanted it to look,
and secondly, because the discipline that I already mentioned was already baked
in. Then I went and put a code review,
and each item of this code review, the agent included in a separate GitHub
issue, also using a skill that I have, because GitHub is a first-class
citizen in all of my work. So,
what it did, it created an issue which included all of these
notes that I found, and it structured them into pieces.
I then prioritized which pieces I wanted most,
for example, to make it look more presentable from the get-go.
I implemented them. And an interesting further piece of work I
did was implementing the upload of PDFs,
which I already showed in the first video.
So, interestingly, it all went in one shot.
I didn't have to change pretty much anything.
Here's how it looked inside the Claude Code web interface
itself. It's nice.
But there are some things you can't go about in one shot, because
an agent will often think too technically.
And so, for example, there was this point in the README where it said
what I would do with more time, and it went for technical choices,
whereas I myself went for more strategic, big-picture choices.
I'm running out of time, so just to finish it:
I even made the whole set of talking points for this video
and the first video with AI as well.
And finally, because Harish mentioned he likes using AI for internal tools,
I have this hook that writes down every cost
spent during the work, based on API rates.
And when you go to the repo itself,
you can run pnpm costs, and it will show you a nice
breakdown of which work took how many dollars.
Or, let's say so, imaginary dollars, because these are API rates,
not what you actually spend with the subscription. Phew,
so I have fifteen seconds left.
It was too short. I hope to discuss it in more detail with you
in the next call.